翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
There are many ways to run our programs in Java.
有很多方法运行 Java 程序
One way is this cute trick I do in my text editor where I press a keyboard shortcut and the output appears on the bottom.
一种方法是编辑器中的技巧，按下快捷键就会在下面输出结果
But let's focus on a workflow that's a little more general,
但我要介绍更一般的工作流
that we expect you guys to get comfortable with in this course.
希望你们在这门课上能够适应
So in this workflow, rather than doing some kind of magic text editor tricks,
在这个工作流中，与文本编辑器中不同的是
we're going to work from a terminal in our operating system.
我们将在操作系统的终端上工作
Now, this is not a Windows or a Mac OS or Linux class,
这不是 Windows、Mac OS 或 Linux 课程
so we're not going to go through the terminal in great detail.
所以我不会详细介绍终端
And we're assuming that you have some familiarity.
我假设你对此有一定的了解
But what I do want to say is that if you're going to go and do a lot of programming in the future,
但如果你将来想要从事大量编程工作
this is really something you want to get acquainted with,
真的应该好好熟悉它
that is, using the terminal on your operating system.
多在自己的操作系统上使用终端
So the usual way, or the most basic way to compile and run a Java program is as follows.
下面是编译运行 Java 程序最常用或者说最基本的方式
So I'm in a folder, and I use the ls command to list the current files.
使用 ls 命令列举当前目录下的文件
And I see there's a file called Helloworld.java.
看到有一个名为 HelloWorld.java 的文件
I want to run that.
我想运行它
So it's actually a two-step process.
一共需要两步
And so what I'm going to do is I'm going to type javac Helloworld and so forth.
第一步输入 javac HelloWorld
Now, a quick tip.
给你一个小贴士
Rather than type out Helloworld.java,
不需要敲完 HelloWorld.java
there's a neat trick where you push tab and it autocompletes.
按下 Tab 键就会自动补全
So use that.
试一下
So I do javac Helloworld.java and press enter.
按下 Enter 键执行 javac HelloWorld.java
So now I'm here, and it seems like nothing's happened.
好像什么都没发生
But if I do ls again, I see a new file has appeared called Helloworld.class.
但是再次执行 ls 会看到一个名为 HelloWorld.class 的新文件出现
World What I've just done is compiled this .java file and turned it into a .class file.
刚才就是编译了 .java 文件，并将其转换成一个 .class 文件
And the old file remains.
旧文件仍然保留
Now if I now want to run Helloworld,
现在想运行 HelloWorld
I type java without the C--
输入 java 没有 c 选项
C means compiler-- so I'd write java Helloworld and press enter.
c 表示编译，所以输入 java HelloWorld 并按 Enter 键
And it does whatever the program is supposed to do, that is, Hello world.
程序运行，打印 Hello world
So this Java program need this class file to run.
所以 Java 程序需要 class 文件才能运行
If I remove that file and try it again, so I do java Helloworld,
如果我删除它重新执行 java HelloWorld
now I get error, could not find class Helloworld.
就会报错“找不到 HelloWorld 类”
So if you're using the command line compilation,
所以使用命令行编译
using just the basic tools javac and java,
只用 javac 和 java 就行了
you'll first need to javac and then java.
先使用 javac 再使用 java
And so to elucidate a little bit more of what's going on,
为了解释这背后发生的事情
I'm going to use the cat command to print out what's in Helloworld.
我要 cat 命令打印出 HelloWorld 的内容
Here's the code.
里面是代码
What Helloworld.class is, it's just another file,
Helloworld.class 只是另一个文件
but instead of having symbols typed out that you and I can understand as humans,
但是它里面的内容无法理解
it's a bunch of weird, strange symbols that were generated by the Java compiler.
它是由 Java 编译器生成的奇怪符号
So some of it makes some sense, but a lot of it just seems like garbage characters.
一些内容看得懂，但其他大多像是垃圾符号
So let's see a schematic view of the whole process.
我们来看一下整个过程的示意图
So compilation.
编译过程
When you run a Java program, the usual thing you're going to do-- it's a two-step process.
运行 Java 程序时，通常是分为两步的过程
You do Hello.java, give that to a compiler,
将 Hello.java 交给编译器
and it generates a .class file.
会生成一个 .class 文件
That .class file can then be given to an interpreter,
然后可以将该 .class 文件提供给解释器
and then stuff will happen.
程序运行
And it could be anything.
可能进行任何操作
It could printing out output.
可能打印输出
It could be playing a song.
可能是在放一首歌
It could be deleting everything on your computer.
可能会删除你计算机上的所有内容
It could be restarting your computer, sending an email, whatever.
可能是重启电脑，或者发送一封电子邮件
The interpreter takes the class file and does whatever it's supposed to do.
解释器获取并运行 class 文件，进行它应该执行的操作
That's not the only way that you could ever run Java code,
这不是运行 Java 代码唯一的方式
but it is the most normal thing to do.
但这是最普通的做法
Even my little text editor trick where I run things like so,
文本编辑器的小技巧底层也是这样
it's really doing this.
它真的是这样做的
You just can't see all the intermediate steps.
只是看不到所有的中间步骤
But you could, in principle, write an interpreter that's able to directly interpret .java code,
原则上你可以编写一个能够直接解释 .java 代码的解释器
but the powers that be have set up the standard process
但标准已经被制定
so that there is an existing compiler tool that creates class files that can be interpreted.
于是有了现成的编译工具创建可解释的 class 文件
So why?
为什么会这样？
Why, oh why, would we ever do Hello.class?
为什么要生成 Hello.class？
Why would we want to make such a file?
为什么生成这样一个文件呢？
Well, one reason is that it's been type checked.
其中一个原因是它已经进行了类型检查
Now, if you're reading the book--
如果你在阅读教材
we haven't talked about static typing yet,
虽然还没有讲到静态类型
but if you've seen static typing already,
但实际你已经见过了
what that means is that when we get out our application to the world,
当我们向外界发布应用程序时
we don't give everyone our .java file.
不会向每个人提供 .java 文件
We give them our .class file.
而是给他们 .class 文件
And because it's been type checked,
因为它已经进行了类型检查
that keeps us safe from type errors,
这可以避免类型错误的影响
and thus our distributed code is safer.
让代码更安全
Next is that .class files are simpler for the machine to execute.
其次，机器执行 .class 文件更简单
And this is for reasons that are a bit beyond the scope of our class,
原因有点超纲
but let's just say that it's a little harder to write an interpreter that efficiently interprets code like this compared to this.
简单说，编写一个直接高效解释代码的解释器要难一些
So this has already been kind of pre-chewed a little.
这些已经提前处理过了
In the same way that I guess eating a bunch of pre-chewed jelly beans is a little easier than solid jelly beans in a bag,
就像嚼过的糖豆比装在袋子里的糖豆更容易吃
so, too, you can think of this as a little bit pre-chewed.
同样，你可以认为这些是嚼过的
And then lastly, there's this minor benefit that since you're not giving out your .java file,
最后还有一个优点，由于分发的不是 .java 文件
nobody knows exactly how your code works.
所以没人确切知道代码的原理
It protects your intellectual property a little bit because you can just give out the .class file.
只分发 .class 文件保护了你的知识产权
Now, that's not a great benefit, because there are actually tools that can take a .class file and give you back a .java file.
但其实不算很大的优点了，因为已经有了一些工具可以反编译 .class 文件为 .java 文件
It's not the exact .java file, but you shouldn't think of it as some kind of great security or anything.
虽然不完全一样，但 .class 文件已经不够安全了
So if you're curious about the compilation process,
对于编译过程来说
you don't really need to know very much about it except for these points,
知道这几点就可以了
but if you're curious about how exactly a compiler works and so forth,
如果你对编译器的底层工作原理感兴趣
there are other courses, CS61C as well as CS164, that you can check out.
可以去看看 CS61C 和 CS164 等课程
But we're not really going to say much more about it.
我们不会讲更多了
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
And we're just going to proceed from here.
就讲这么多